(桂)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ～！
Elizabeth!
[In order to rescue the captured Elizabeth, they are learning the secrets of ninja.]
[Now, the Go-Ninja begins their ninja training. Isn't it a bit late?!]
["Mom's Busy, Too, So Quit Complaining About What's for Dinner"]
(さっちゃん)
それじゃあ これから➡
[TOGAKUSHI GINZA]
Now, I'm going to test your ninja skills.
あなたたちの忍者適性を
見させてもらうから…｡
(さっちゃん)ここはね
通称 忍者通りと呼ばれ➡
This place is commonly known as "Ninja Street." And we ninja often use it for training.
私たち忍者が修業する際
よく使われているところなの｡
江戸で活躍する忍者は
みんな ここで➡
Every ninja active in Edo, first learned the art of becoming a shadow right here.
影になる術を身につけ
巣立っていくのよ｡
(新八)でも 何もありませんよ｡
But there's nothing here. It's just an ordinary street lined with shops.
ただの商店街じゃないですか…｡
ｽﾎﾟｰﾂｼﾞﾑで忍者になれるとでも
思ってんのか？ ﾃﾒｴは！
Oh, so you think you can become a ninja at a sports gym?! Die, four-eyed bastard!
ﾒｶﾞﾈ 死ね！ この野郎!!
なに!?
What?! Why are you acting so sadistic to me?
なんで ﾎﾞｸに対してはＳなの!?
(桂)なるほど…｡
I see. When learning how to hide, it's best to do it in a place filled with people!
人から身を隠す術は
人のなかにあってこそ➡
身につけられるということか…｡
That's right. And, why are you holding that plate of curry?
そういうことよ…
で なんで ｶﾚｰ持ってるの？
(銀時)で 具体的に何をやるわけ？
So, what are we supposed to do here?
みんな あれを見て！
Everyone, look over there!
ん？ 本屋か？ なるほど…｡
[MINMEIDO BOOKSTORE]
Huh? A bookstore?
I see. We must shoplift some books without being caught by the store clerk...
店員に気づかれないように
本を万引き…｡
いい？ これから店員にも客にも
気づかれることなく➡
Listen. You've got to buy a porno magazine without being noticed by the clerk or the customers.
好みのｴﾛ本を買ってきなさい！
はぁ!? 何ですか？ それ｡
そんなん 忍者と関係ねえじゃん！
What?! What are you taking about? What the hell does that have to do with being a ninja?!
これは 忍者ｽｸｰﾙにも
正式採用されている立派な試験よ｡
This is a good test, officially used at the ninja academy.
みんな ここを通って
大人になっていったの｡
Everyone must complete this test before they can become an adult.
違う意味の大人じゃん！
That's quite a different meaning of "Adult"!
じゃあ あなた できるの？
Then, can you do it?
完全に己の気配を断ち➡
You must completely hide all signs of your presence
誰に気づかれることなく
素早い判断で好みのｴﾛ本を選ぶ｡
and, without being noticed, quickly judge which is your favorite porno mag.
店員にも気づかれないよう
代金を払い➡
Then, you have to pay without the cashier noticing you
何事もなかったかのように去る…｡
and leave as if nothing happened.
どう？ できる？
Do you think you can do it?
《あっ やっぱ
そういう趣味なんだ？》
Ah... Now we know what's her favorite...
ﾌﾝ 怖気づいたか… ｷｻﾏら｡
You guys are too self-conscious.
これしきのことでなれるなら
忍者も大したことはないな｡
If that's all I have to do to become a ninja, that's easy.
見ておけ… こんなもの 朝飯前｡
Watch me. This is a piece of cake...um...curry.
いや ｶﾚｰどき前だ！
おい ｶﾚｰは
置いてったほうがいいって！
Watch me. This is a piece of cake...uh...curry.
絶対 ｼﾞｬﾏだって！
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒあるよ 絶対 離しちゃ!!
Don't drop it! You'll die if you spill it, Curry Ninja!
お前は それをこぼすと死ぬからな
ｶﾚｰﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ！
(桂)ﾙｰｼﾞｬ！
(神楽)ﾙｰｼﾞｬ!!
Rouxger!
[Note: Roux (spice mix) is used to make curry in Japan. A parody mix of Roux + Roger]
ﾙｰｼﾞｬって何だよ！ ﾗｼﾞｬｰだろ!!
What's a Rouxger?! I've never heard such an absurd word. Do you mean "Roger"?!
聞いたことねえよ！
そんな了解のしかた!!
速い！
大したものだわ｡
He's fast!
It's quite something. He's even faster than a real ninja...
ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞは
まったく忍者に引けをとらない｡
おいおい
いけんじゃねえの？ これ｡
Hey, hey. He might make it...
(みんな)あっ！
He spilled his curry!
ｶ… ｶﾚｰ こぼした！
すまん… ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ｡
S-Sorry...Leader... Take care...of the rest...
あとは 頼む… うぅっ…｡
(神楽)ｶﾚｰﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ！
Curry Ninja!
あれほど こぼすなと
言ったｱﾙのに…｡
Above all else, I told you not to spill the curry.
Ｂね… ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞは評価できるけど
注意力が まるでﾀﾞﾒ｡
I give him a "B." He had good speed, but sucky concentration. Who's next?
次は？
私が行くよ！
I'll go!
ｶﾚｰﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰの仇は 私が討つね！
I shall avenge Curry Ninja.
(さっちゃん)あなたは
ｴﾛ本 買っていい歳じゃないから➡
You're not old enough to buy adult magazines, so buy JUMP instead.
『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』買ってきなさい！
Wow! She's like a ninja! So ninja-like!
おっ 忍者っぽい 忍者っぽいよ!!
やる気満々だな…｡
She's ready and willing. She loves this kind of stuff!
ｱｲﾂ こんなの好きだからな｡
うぉ～ ﾉﾘﾉﾘですよ｡
Wow! She's in the zone!
いいから 早く買ってこいって
言ってんだよ！
Come on! Go ahead and buy it!
Huh? She's coming back. What happened?
あれ？ 戻ってきましたよ｡
どうしたんだろう？
ん？ 泣いてんのか？
Huh? Is she crying?
銀ちゃ～ん…
道に 犬のｳﾝｺ 落ちてた｡
Gin-chan...There was dog poop on the street. I'm all icky!
どうしよう…｡
ｷﾞｬｱ～！
(桂)ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ 心配するな！
それは おそらく➡
Leader, don't worry about it. I think it's just the curry I spilled... No, that stinks!
[Ninja Hattori-kun character]
[Get 10 Times More Points]
ｵﾚが さっき
こぼしたｶﾚｰ… くさっ！
(神楽)気休めはよせよ ｶﾚｰﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ！
That's just as bad!! Curry Ninja! Well, I'm the real Curry Ninja now!
(神楽)いや
ﾎﾝﾄのｶﾚｰﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰは 私さ！
Don't get so wound-up. I'll give you an "A."
(さっちゃん)ﾔｹにならないで！
Ａ評価 あげるから!!
(神楽)同情してんじゃねえよ
ﾁｷｼｮｰ！ やってられっか!!
I don't need your sympathy grades!! Damn it!
That's it! I don't care about being the leader anymore!
(神楽)何がﾘｰﾀﾞｰだ！
しようがねえな…
ｵﾚが やるしかねえか！
It can't be helped. I have to do it...
こう見えても ｶﾞｷの頃は
忍者ごっことかやってたんだぜ！
I may not look it, but as a kid, I pretended to be a ninja all the time.
がんばって！ 銀さん｡
Good luck, Gin-san!
あれ？
どこ行ったんですか？ 銀さん｡
Huh?
Where did Gin-san go?
あっ… 汚っ！
That's gross!
いいえ｡ 汚くなんかないわ｡
No, it's not. That's a good technique.
あれは 隠れ身という
立派な忍法のひとつ｡
One of the real ninja arts, called "Kakuremi no jutsu."
さすが 銀さん 発想が違うわ！
I'm so proud of Gin-san. He's such a gifted thinker.
なんか 甘くねえ!?
ひいきだよ ひいき！
Are you going easy on him?!
Teacher's pet!
(さっちゃん)なに？
文句あんの？ ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙｶﾚｰ｡
What?! Any objections, Double Curry?
(桂)ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙｶﾚｰって なんだ？
好きで着ているわけではないわ！
What's "Double Curry?" I didn't come up with this yellow suit!
(さっちゃん)言っておくけどね
それ➡
Let me tell you something. It's not made of yellow cloth.
黄色い生地で
できてんじゃないから！
It's made out of a yellowed white curtain. So it's "Yellowed Ninja."
黄ばんだ白いｶｰﾃﾝで
作ったﾔﾂだから ｷﾊﾞﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ！
(桂)ｷｻﾏ!! そこになおれ！
たたき斬ってくれる！
Bastard, get over here! I'll tear you apart!
(神楽)やめろ ｲｴﾛｰ！
指令にさからうなｱﾙ!!
Stop, Yellow! Don't disobey my orders!
But, Leader!
(桂)しかし ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！
(収集員)なして こんなとこに
ｺﾞﾐなんかあったんだべか？
Why is there a garbage bin here?
(収集員)知らね｡
Heck if I know.
(収集車の走行音)
Well... That's bad, isn't it?
ねぇ やばいんじゃないすか あれ｡
(さっちゃん)気のせいでしょ？
It's just our imagination. No one's actually inside it, right?
ﾎﾝﾄは
誰も入ってなかったんじゃない？
Maybe so... If he were inside, he'd be dead.
そうｱﾙね！ あんなん入ってたら
死んじゃうｱﾙもんね！
じゃあ 次は 新八君の番ね！
Well... You're next, Shinpachi-kun.
あっ はい… いってきます！
All right. Then I'm off.
♪♪～
あれ？
ちょっと…｡
Oh?
Well...
(神楽)なんか すんなりよ｡
He's quite smooth...
(桂)全然 気づかれてない
っていうか…｡
Nobody notices him at all... Or, maybe...
(神楽)誰も ﾔﾂの存在なんて
気にかけてねえ！
Nobody cares about his existence.
(桂)存在感 うすっ！
He has a non-presence!
Come on. I don't care about ninjas or whatever. Anybody can do that as long as they're plain.
なんだよ おい…
忍者もｸｿもねえじゃねえか｡
地味だったら
誰でもいけるんじゃねえかよ｡
(さっちゃん)
やっぱ 入ってたのか！
He really was inside!
ﾊﾞｶらしい… よかったよ！
こんな茶番 参加しなくて!!
That's stupid. I'm glad I didn't do it that way.
いや これは あれだよ｡
This is just... I just went to the restroom and tangled with a punk.
さっき 便所に行ったら
ﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗに からまれて…｡
いや ﾎﾝﾄだって！ ﾏｼﾞで!!
It's true. Seriously... Why are you all looking at me like that?
なに？ その目！
[South Town Magistrate's office]
I see...
(遠山)ほぅ さようか…｡
(遠山)桂が ついに動いたか…｡
Finally Katsura makes his move.
(全蔵)どうやら 仲間を募って➡
It seems he has gathered a force to free the beast. They'll most likely attack tonight.
あのﾊﾞｹﾓﾉを奪還せんと
画策してる様子…｡
おそらく 今宵にも
乗り込んでくるものかと…｡
(遠山)かかったな…｡
He fell for it... The moth is flying into the flame...
飛んで火に入る夏の虫とは
まさに このこと…｡
幕府の天敵 攘夷派浪士の
桂 小太郎…｡
Bakufu's enemy, Leader of the Anti-Foreign rebels, Kotaro Katsura...
そのｸﾋﾞをとったとならば
ﾜｼの幕府の地位も磐石というもの｡
If I get his head, my status in the Bakufu will rise.
頼んだぞ… 服部 全蔵！
I'm counting on you... Zenzo Hattori...
(かけ声)
いくか！
Here we go...
Ninja Spy Force, Go-Ninja!
忍者戦隊ｺﾞﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ！
(みんな)参る!!
Forward!
[Gin Tama Shippuden]
You know, they say that having moonlight in your butt hole is healthy.
(見回り)月の光をさ
ｹﾂの穴に浴びせると➡
健康に いいらしいよ…｡
You, watch what you say while we're on duty!
(見回り)ｷｻﾏ 勤務中に
何を言い出すかと思えば…｡
いや… ﾏｼﾞだって！ ふだんさ
肛門に光なんて当たらないじゃん｡
Seriously... Usually, the butt hole doesn't get any light.
まぁ 太陽でも
いいらしいんだけど➡
Sunlight also works, but moonlight works a lot better.
月光は ﾊﾝﾊﾟねえらしいぜ｡
ｷｻﾏ また そんなこと言って➡
You're saying something like that just to antagonize me.
拙者を たばかるつもりだろう！
Seriously... I heard Hattori-san cured his hemorrhoids that way.
(見回り)いや ﾏｼﾞだって！
服部さんが それで➡
痔を治したらしいよ｡
(見回り)いいかげんにしろ！
あの桂が この奉行所内に➡
That's enough! Katsura might be here on the magistrate's property.
入り込んでいるかも
しれぬのだぞ！
Well, I was trying to lighten the mood... Damn it! I have to pee!
いや 緊張を
ほぐそうと思って… やべえ…｡
ｵﾚ ちょっと 小便 行ってくる！
(見回り)おい!!
Ah! Hey!
まったく… 緊張感のないﾔﾂだ｡
Really... Is this guy really brave or just nuts?
お月様 どうか
拙者のｲﾎﾞ痔を治してくだされ～!!
Moon! Please cure my hemorrhoids!
えっ？ あれ？ 月が 近づいて…｡
Ah?
The moon is coming closer...
(見回り)うおっ!! おぉ～っ！
(見回り)あぁ～っ!!
[SERIOUSLY CENSORED]
Sorry, but you should go see a doctor to cure your hemorrhoids.
悪いな…
痔は 医者に治してもらえや｡
White Ninja! Special technique: Ninja Art: "Undercover Strike"
＜必殺技 忍法 隠れ身の術！＞
It stinks!
ﾊﾞｯﾄﾞ ｽﾒﾙ！
(見回り)おい 何を騒いで…｡
Hey, What's all the racket...?
あっ ｷｻﾏ！
くせ者!!
Oh, you!
I-Intruder!!
(見回り)あっ 明かりが！
何も見えん!!
The light... I can't see anything.
あら それは大変！
Oh, that's not good. You need to put on your glasses.
ﾒｶﾞﾈをかけなくちゃ…｡
なに？ これ くさっ！
なに これ!?
What's this? It stinks! What's this?
くさっ！ とれねえぞ!!
納豆か？ これ｡
It stinks! I can't take them off! Is this natto?!
Four-eyed Ninja! Special Technique: Ninja Art: "Without Glasses I Can't See Tomorrow"
＜必殺技 忍法 ﾒｶﾞﾈがないと
明日も見えない＞
うおぉ～ ｲﾔだ～!!
Whoa! No!
ひょっとして 一生このままなの？
絶対ｲﾔだぁ～!!
Am I gonna be like this forever?! No way!
Ah, but I might like this, because it feels so good...
あぁ～ でも
これ結構 気持いいかも！
うん
今年これ くるかも 納豆ﾒｶﾞﾈ！
Right, this will be a big hit this year. Natto glasses.
Huh? Who are you?
(２人)あれっ 誰？ ｷﾐ｡
ﾍｯ｡
Holstein Ninja!
＜必殺技 忍法➡
Special Technique: Ninja Art: "Even though I'm in a Holstein costume, I'm still just a plain guy."
｢とりあえず
ﾎﾙｽﾀｲﾝにしたけど やっぱ地味｣＞
(見回りたち)出会え 出会え～！
Really... Such a beautiful moon tonight...
(見回り)ったく
こんな きれいな月夜に…｡
Let's take care of 'em quick and get back to moon bathing!
(見回り)さっさと済ませて
月でも見ながら 一杯やろうや！
I see. Then how about some moony-side-up egg curry!
(桂)ほぅ ならば
月見ｶﾚｰは どうだ！
Red, Hot! Yellow, Mild!
Double Curry Ninja Special Technique  Ninja Art: "Throwing Curry In a Hurry"
＜必殺技 忍法➡
｢なんか
めっちゃ ｶﾚｰ投げてくる！｣＞
(騒ぎ声)
I see.
(全蔵)なるほど
下手な隠密戦術は捨て➡
They're throwing everything into a state of confusion instead of working out an undercover plan.
四方を攪乱する作戦に出たか｡
素人にしては 上出来だな｡
It's a very good plan for amateurs. But it won't work against us... Real ninja.
だが ｵﾚたちには通用しねえよ｡
本物の忍者にはな｡
Damn it! Where did they go?
(見回りたち)どこだ!? 捜せ～！
Find them!
(神楽)銀ちゃん もっと詰めてよ！
Gin-chan! Can you move over more?! My shoulder is sticking out.
It'll get attacked! They'll get my shoulder!!
私 肩出てる やられる｡
肩 もっていかれる！
(桂)ｵﾚに至っては 丸出しだぞ｡
In my case, all of me is sticking out! They'll get all of me!!
やられる！ 全部もっていかれる!!
Get out, you guys! This is for one person only. I built this by myself, for myself.
出て行け お前ら｡
これは 一人用なんだよ｡
ｵﾚが ｵﾚのために作ったんだよ！
Anyway, why did you make it look like brick?! This isn't New York!
ってか なんで ﾚﾝｶﾞ作り？
ここは ﾆｭｰﾖｰｸじゃねえんだよ！
(さっちゃん)文句があるなら
出て行きなさい！
If you have any complaints, get out! I'll hide anywhere, even in a sewage canal, as long as it's with Gin-san.
私は 銀さんと一緒なら
ﾄﾞﾌﾞ川でも住みます！
Shut up. You're bothering me, too!
うるせえよ お前もｼﾞｬﾏだ！
Whatever, you really stink. Don't touch me!
どうでもいいけど
お前 なんか臭いんだけど｡
あんまり 寄んないでくれる！
Humph. I love it when you talk rough...
ﾌﾝｯ！ もっと蔑みなさい｡
それが 私の糧となる…！
ﾎﾝﾄに臭い！
なんか納豆臭い！ ﾌｨﾝｶﾞｰ!!
You really stink! You smell like natto! Your fingers!
あれっ ｲｴﾛｰｶﾚｰは？
Huh? Where's Yellow Curry Ninja?
Hey, what are you doing, Zura?!
って なにやってんだ ﾂﾞﾗ～！
I'm not Zura. I'm a pine tree!
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 松だ｡
いやﾑﾘ！ ﾑﾘだって!!
No, no! Impossible! You're totally in the open!
ほとんど 丸出しじゃねえか！
ん？
(神楽)銀ちゃん あれ見て！
Gin-chan, look over there!
Elizabeth!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！ うおぉ～!!
ﾂﾞﾗ 待て！
Zura, wait!
(見回り)あっ 賊だ！ 待て～!!
Ah, it's the intruder!! Stop!
おい見ろ ここの壁 おかしいぞ！
Hey, look! This wall is strange! Like part of it is in New York!
ここだけ ﾆｭｰﾖｰｸだ！
ｹﾞｯ！
ﾂﾞﾗ～！ ﾃﾒｴ
なにしてくれてんだぁ!!
Zura! What are you doing?!
ﾎﾜｲﾄ！ みんな！
一緒に来てくれるのか｡
White! Everyone! Please stick with me.
ﾃﾒｴのせいで ﾊﾞﾚたんだよ！
殺害すんぞ ｺﾗｧ!!
It's your fault they found us!
I'll SATSUGAI you!
[NOTE: This is a spoof of the manga Detroit Metal City.]
うわぁ ｶﾚｰが こぼれちゃうよ
死んじゃうよ～！
My curry is going to spill! I'm going to die!
もう ｷｬﾗはいいから 捨てろ～！
Forget about your character, just throw it away!
Oh, no... If we don't do something, we'll end up getting destroyed.
まずいわね
このままでは 全滅だわ｡
Sachan-san, do you have any useful weapons?
さっちゃんさん
何か いい道具は ないんですか!?
(さっちゃん)任せて…
足止めには これ！
Count on me! This will slow them down!
Maki...
[Note: Makibishi are small, spiked caltrops used by ninja to deter pursuing enemies.]
まき び しぃ～！
bi...
shi!
(見回り)己 これでは近づけぬ！
Damn it! We can't get any closer with these.
おっ！ うまいこと
ﾊﾞﾘｱみたいに なりましたよ｡
Oh! It worked perfectly as a barrier.
Just as I planned. That was Ninja Art Makibishi Circle.
狙いどおりだわ｡
忍法 まきびしｻｰｸﾙよ｡
ｳｿつけ！ 刺さってんぞ!!
You liar! It's stuck in your forehead!
Take that!
おらぁ くらえ！
死ね ｺﾗｧ！
Die!
違う！ 使い方 間違ってる｡
That's totally wrong! That's not how Makibishi are supposed to be used!
まきびしは
そういう感じじゃない！
♪♪～
(ｵﾍﾟﾚｰﾀｰ)お奉行！ 次々と➡
Magistrate!!
They're breaking through the mechanical traps, one after another! At this rate, they'll be here soon.
からくりﾄﾗｯﾌﾟが
突破されています！
このままでは じき ここにも…｡
ﾌﾌｯ 案ずることはない｡
Don't worry about it. There's still...the final room...
最後の間には…｡
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
What's this place?
なんだ ここ？
Hey!
おい あれ！
That's!
Elizabeth!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
ﾀﾞﾒ！ 近寄っちゃ!!
No! Don't get any closer...
ぬおぉ…！
ｴ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
E-Elizabeth...
(全蔵)ｸｸｯ 残念だったな｡
That's too bad.
Elizabeth-chan isn't here.
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽちゃんは
ここには いないよ｡
なっ！
お前は！
You are...
ｸｸｯ 久しぶりだな 猿飛 あやめ｡
Long time no see, Ayame Sarutobi.
さっちゃんさん
全蔵！
知ってるんですか？
Zenzo...
Sachan-san, you know this guy?
He's a former Oniwabanshu. Zenzo Hattori...
(さっちゃん)元お庭番衆 筆頭
服部 全蔵｡
お庭番衆の歴史上
最も恐れられた 随一の忍術使い｡
He possessed the most feared ninja techniques in the history of the Oniwabanshu.
今は ﾌﾘｰで
ここの旦那に雇われててね｡
I'm a freelancer now and I've been working for the big man here.
I'm sorry, but even if you are my ex co-worker, if you insist on sticking with these fools I'll show no mercy.
悪いが 元同僚とはいえ
そっちに つくなら容赦はしねえ｡
ｺﾞﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰだか なんだか知らねえが➡
I don't care if you're a Go-Ninja or what...
にわか忍者じゃ
本物の忍者には勝てねえよ｡
But an amateur ninja can't beat a real ninja.
いや たとえ 侍でもなぁ！
Even if you are a samurai...
We are...the strongest five.
ｵﾚたちが 最強の五忍だ｡
Idaten no Gou!
[Note: Idaten = a devoted guardian]
(剛)韋駄天の剛！
Bishamonten no Shuwa!
[Note: Bishamonten = the chief of the Four Heavenly Kings]
(修輪)毘沙門天の 修輪！
Benzaiten Kaoru!
[Note: Benzaiten = the Hindu goddess of wealth and eloquence]
(薫)弁財天 薫よん｡
Komokuten Matsuo.
[Note: Komokuten = one of the Four Heavenly Kings]
(松尾)広目天 松尾｡
Marishiten, Zenzo Hattori.
[Marishiten = the goddess of heaven and light]
摩利支天 服部 全蔵｡
５人 揃って…｡
We're five are...
Freelance Battle Squad, The Shinobi Five!
(みんな)ﾌﾘｰﾀｰ戦隊 ｼﾉﾋﾞ５！
ﾊ～ﾊｯﾊ！ 桂～!!
Katsura! No, Go-Ninja, this game will soon be over!
いや ｺﾞﾆﾝｼﾞｬｰ｡
年貢の納めどきだ｡
All members of the Shinobi Five used to work for the Oniwabanshu, and they're very good.
ｼﾉﾋﾞ５は いずれも
お庭番を務めていた猛者ばかり｡
You'll die in front of your beloved Elizabeth-chan.
かわいい ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽちゃんの目の前で
朽ち果てるがよい！
Elizabeth!
(桂)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
Gin-san!
銀さん！
(剛)ｸｸｸ…｡
お前らの相手は ｵﾚたちだよ｡
We're your opponent...
JUMP Samurai!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ侍～！
銀さん！
Gin-san!
まさか
こんなところで会えるとはなぁ｡
I never thought I would meet you in a place like this.
ｵﾚぁ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ 読むたびに
ﾃﾒｴの顔が ﾁﾗついて➡
Every time I read JUMP, your face appears in my mind, and it's so annoying!
ｲﾗｲﾗしちまうんだよ！
待て待て｡
Wait, wait... Let's see... JUMP... JUMP...
え～と ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ… あぁ あれだ｡
Oh, I've got it! Are you the Isomura-kun to whom I never returned the copy of JUMP?!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ 借りたっきり
返してなかった磯村君？
待て あれには訳が…｡
Wait, let me explain...
I told you, I'm Hattori.
服部って 言ってんだろうが～！
お前 なに？
まさか ｵﾚのこと忘れたのかぁ！
Hey, you! What?! Don't tell me you forgot about me!
だから 磯村君でしょ？
So, you're Isomura-kun, right?
服部だぁ～！
I'm Ha-tto-ri!
Sorry, but I'm not good at remembering a
悪いな 男の顔 覚えんのは➡
man's face!
得意じゃねえんだ！
だったら ｵﾚも覚えてねえ！
If that's the case, I don't remember you, either! I don't know who you are!
ﾃﾒｴなんか 知らねえ！
Then...
じゃあ やり合う理由がねえだろ！
There's no reason to fight!
Shut up!
(全蔵)うるせえ！
I don't have to remember you to hate you!
覚えてねえけど
なんか 腹立つんだよ～！
Gin-san, be careful!
銀さん 気をつけて｡
That man is very dangerous...
その人は 本当に危険…｡
(薫)気をつけるのは あなたよん｡
You're the one who needs to be careful.
(薫)ﾌﾌﾌｯ さすがだわ｡
その身のこなし まさしく猿｡
Ah, what wonderful agility! You move just like a monkey.
あ～ら ごめんなさい｡
｢さっちゃん｣って➡
Oh, I'm sorry. Do I have to call you Sachan? Osaru-san.
[Note: Osaru-san = monkey girl]
呼ばなきゃいけなかった
んだっけ？ お猿さん｡
You're...the ninja academy Madonna, Kaoru-san Waki?
あなた 忍者学校のﾏﾄﾞﾝﾅ
脇 薫さん？
ごめんなさい
ｹﾊﾞくて わからなかったわ｡
I'm sorry, but I didn't recognize you because you're much too flashy.
(剛)ﾌﾝｯ あの桂が
こんな優男だったとはな｡
Humph. I didn't know Katsura was such a weakling.
おまけに他２人は ｶﾞｷ｡
Not only that, but the other two are just kids.
According to my data, our chance of winning is 99.8%.
私のﾃﾞｰﾀでは
勝率99.8ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄですよ｡
What do we do? I don't think we can win against real ninja.
どうしましょう
忍者なんてﾎﾞｸ 勝てる気が…｡
(神楽)ｶﾚｰ 用意！
ｶﾚｰ!? ないない！
Curry, ready!
Curry? No! No! Don't say that like it's nothing!
当たり前のように 言わないで！
What the hell kind of battle cry is that?!
持ってるわけないでしょ
そんなもん！
Agh!! They've got them too! Has everyone gone insane or is it just me?
って用意してるしよ！
なにっ ﾎﾞｸが おかしいの!?
ﾎﾞｸの16年の人生
間違ってましたか!?
Unfortunately, we already calculated your chances.
残念ながら ｷﾐたちの技のﾃﾞｰﾀは
算出済みです｡
99.8ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄの確率で
封じられると 出ていますよ｡
If you strike, you face a 99.8% probability of being slaughtered.
うるせえ！
やってみなきゃ わかんねえだろ!!
Shut up! We won't know that until we try! Don't underestimate our Triple Curry!
ﾄﾘﾌﾟﾙｶﾚｰ ﾅﾒんなよ～！
ﾄﾘﾌﾟﾙ!? ﾎﾞｸも入ってんの？
Triple? Does that mean I'm in, too? Hey, am I also a member?!
それ ﾎﾞｸも入ってんの!?
We'll show you the difference between fake and real ninja!
ﾆｾﾓﾉと本物の差を
思い知るがいい！
(松尾たち)うおぉ～！
Hot! A potato down my back! A potato is dancing on my back!
ｱﾂﾂﾂﾂ…！
(桂)ｱﾂｱﾂｱﾂ…！
(神楽)熱～い!!
Hot!
ｲﾓが 背中に！
ｲﾓが 背中で踊ってる!!
(剛)同じ技でも
ここまで 差が出る｡
We used the same technique, but with different results...This is the difference in our skills!
(剛)これが
お前たちと ｵﾚたちの 実力の差だ｡
食ってる!?
They're eating it!
なんてこった… ﾎﾞｸらの技は➡
Good grief... Our technique was completely outclassed.
完全に見切られていたってのか…｡
(剛)ﾌﾌﾌ だから甘いというんだ｡
You're more naïve than I thought!
(桂)ﾌｯ 甘いのは ｷｻﾏらのほうだ｡
You're the ones who are naive.
なにを…｡
(３人)うっ！
What...
うぉっ 腹が…｡
Ugh! My stomach...
My stomach... You bastard, What did you do to that curry?!
(松尾)腹が…｡
ｷｻﾏ まさか ｶﾚｰに…｡
(桂)ﾌﾌﾌ 知らない人から
もらったものを食べるな と➡
Didn't your mommy tell you not to eat food from a stranger?
母親に習わなかったのか？
己の技を誇示したいあまりに
墓穴を掘ったな｡
You dug your own graves by showing off your technique.
忍術を学ぶ前に 常識を学べ｡
ｵﾒｴもな｡
Learn common sense before learning ninja techniques.
You, too...
(神楽)ぐおぉ…！
Leader! What happened?!
(桂)ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！ どうした!?
You, how could you?! I was a little hungry, so I had a bite!
ﾃﾒｴ なんてことしてくれんだ…
小腹が空いて ちょっと➡
つまんじまったじゃねえか…｡
お前も食ってたんかい！
You ate it, too?!
おのれ… これしきの便意に
負けるものか…｡
Well... I can overcome this kind of pain.
The kanji character "Shinobi" also means "to endure". Keep that in mind...
忍の文字には 耐え忍ぶという
意味もあることを➡
忘れてもらっては困る…｡
我が忍術 見せてくれよう！
I'll show you my true ninja technique!
Ninja Art, "Shadow Clone Technique"!
忍法 分身の術!!
(剛)ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ…！
どれが本物か わかるかな？
You'll never figure out which is the real me!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
You're completely unprotected!
丸出しじゃねえか!!
ごぶぁっ!!
(松尾)剛！ なんてこった
剛が あっちのほうも GO…｡
Gou! Oh, no! Gou say something...
(修輪)おのれ… 次は ｵﾚの番だ｡
And... Now it's my turn.
忍法 怒品愚!!
Ninja Art, "Steroid Jutsu!"
Grow huge, my muscles!
膨れ上がれ 我が筋肉よ!!
…あ？
別のところが
膨れ上がってんじゃねえか!!
Something got huge, anyway!!
まずい…｡ 私のﾃﾞｰﾀによると
このままでは 次のｶｯﾄで➡
This isn't good... According to my data, there's a 99.8% probability I'll be beaten in the next scene.
倒される確率が 99.8…｡
このｶｯﾄじゃ！
This scene!
H-Hey! What are you guys doing?
おい… なにやってんだ ﾃﾒｴら！
服部！ どういうことだ？
最高の五忍じゃなかったのか!?
Hattori! What's is this? I thought you guys were the five greatest ninjas in the world!!
That's all wrong. The Pegasus Meteor Attack is like this...
(全蔵)ちげえよ！ ﾍﾟｶﾞｻｽ流星斬は
ここから こうしてだな…｡
ﾊﾞｶ お前！ あれは
ﾍﾟｶﾞｻｽ座の軌跡を描いてんだよ！
Idiot. It's supposed to look like the Pegasus constellation.
(遠山)服部 ﾃﾒｴ なにやってんだ！
中学生の休み時間か!!
Hattori! What are you doing? This isn't middle school recess!
(服部)お奉行！
ﾍﾟｶﾞｻｽ流星斬 あれ こうっすよね？
Magistrate! The Pegasus Meteor Attack! It's like this, right?
[Note: Parody of the pegasasu ryusei ken technique from the JUMP manga/anime Saint Seiya]
Magistrate! Give him a clear "no" sign! This guy is an idiot! Idiot!
お奉行！ ｶﾞﾂﾝと言ってやって｡
ﾊﾞｶだ ｺｲﾂ｡ ﾊﾞｶ！
(遠山)２人とも ﾊﾞｶだろうが！
ちなみに あの技は こうだ！
Both of you are idiots! Anyway, that technique is done like this! I recorded all the episodes!
ｱﾆﾒ 全部 録画してるんだ！
You know, you were popular with certain boys, but they were all disgusting. Glasses fanatics...
ｱﾝﾀさぁ 学校で
一部の男子に 人気あったけど➡
なんか みんな ｷﾓかったわよね｡
ﾒｶﾞﾈ 萌え～ とか｡
脇さん あなたの親友の
関さん いるじゃない？
Waki-san, your best friend Seki-san... She talks behind your back...
あの人 陰で
あなたの悪口 言ってたわよ｡
(遠山)ﾃﾒｴらは なに 女特有の
陰険な戦い 繰り広げてんだ！
Is that what you call a fight?!
銀さん！ 早く 決着つけないと➡
Gin-san!
We've got to end this quickly!
神楽ちゃんが
ﾋﾛｲﾝ史上 最低の暴挙に!!
Kagura-chan's been struck by the worst blow ever suffered by a heroine!
なんか いまいち ﾓﾁﾍﾞｰｼｮﾝがな｡
For some reason, I'm not especially motivated.
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが どうなろうが➡
I don't care about Elizabeth or if Kagura gets her feet wet.
神楽が もらそうが
どうでもよくてよ｡
Just wait...it'll I get better, shag-head! I'll poop more than my pants!
(神楽)ﾃﾒｴ！
私が復活した暁には➡
目の前で ｳﾝｺしてやるからな…｡
ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ 落ち着け！
いいか？ ｵﾚの呼吸に合わせろ｡
Leader, you gotta relax! Take deep breaths like me. C'mon.
ひっひっふ～｡
What is she, pooping or having a baby?!
出る～！ それ 出るほうのﾔﾂ～!!
(争う声)
Everyone's so noisy... It's time for the showdown.
(全蔵)外野が
うるさくなってきた｡
そろそろ 決着つけるとするか｡
そうだな｡
All right.
ﾃﾒｴとは やけに 話が合うな｡
You and I think alike... I wish we'd met under different circumstances.
もっと違う出会い方
したかったもんだぜ｡
いや だから…➡
...Is that so...
前に 違う会い方してるって…➡
Well, we already met under different circumstances!! I already told you!
言ってんだろうがぁ!!
♪♪～
…消えた!?
...He disappeared?
銀さん 危ない!!
Gin-san! Look out!
He's below me... How annoying.
下か！ こざかしい｡
《なんだ？
この 甘ったりい におい…》
What's this? Some sort of sweet scent...
My body...is numb!
《体が… しびれて…》
(薫)ﾎｰｯﾎｯﾎ！
私の ﾊﾞﾗの香りは どう？
How do my roses smell?
忍法 呪縛旋花！
Ninja Art, "Coiling Aroma Attack!" Paralyzing all who sniff my poison rose!
私の 毒ﾊﾞﾗの香りを嗅いだ者は
身動きひとつ とれなくなるわよ｡
(薫)さぁ 今よ 全蔵！
とどめをさしなさい！
Now, Zenzo! It's time for the final blow!
(薫)ｵｰｯﾎｯﾎ！
ﾁｯ…｡
(さっちゃん)臨 兵 闘 者…｡
Saru! How can she move?! My technique didn't work?
(薫)猿… なんで 動けるの？
私の技が効いてない!?
(薫)まさか 納豆のにおいで
私のﾊﾞﾗの香りを かき消した!?
Don't tell me she used the smell of natto to cancel out the scent of my roses?!
忍法 ねば～ぎぶあっぷ!!
Ninja Art!
I will Natto give up!
Wake up, Gin-san!
よみがえれ 銀さぁ～ん!!
(全蔵)死ねぇ！
Die!
JUMP Samurai!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ侍!!
The one to die...
死ぬのは… ﾃﾒｴだ!!
is you!
(全蔵)ぐわぁっ！
(薫)全蔵！ 全蔵！
Zenzo! Zenzo!
ひどいじゃない！
全蔵はね 痔を患って…｡
You're so mean! Zenzo has hemorrhoids! It stinks!
くさっ！
ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな… ｼﾉﾋﾞ５が…｡
Th-This can't be...The Shinobi Five... No way...
そんなﾊﾞｶな… ん？
(遠山)ぐわぁ～っ!!
(神楽)おぉ～っ！
間に合えばいいですけど…
神楽ちゃん｡
I hope Kagura-chan makes it in time.
…あぁ～っ!!
Eli...Elizabeth!
(桂)ｴﾘ… ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ～！
Oh, my goodness! Elizabeth! It's terrible! Absolutely terrible! Oh, no... This is...awful!
なんてこった ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが！
ひどい… ひどいぞ！
そんな！ あれだ… ひどいぞ～！
Hey, Zura... Isn't this kinda weird? It looks like something cottony is coming out...
なぁ ﾂﾞﾗ あれ おかしくねえか？
中から 綿みてえなのが…｡
That's right. And there's no blood, either.
あぁ ﾎﾝﾄだ｡
それに 血とかも出てませんよ｡
あり？
Huh?
I already told you fools.
(全蔵)だから言っただろう｡
ここには
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽちゃんは いねえって｡
Elizabeth-chan isn't here. Elizabeth-chan was never here!!
最初から
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽちゃんなんて いねえんだよ｡
まだ わかんないの？
You still don't you get it? Katsura, that old man...made an Elizabeth doll to lure you here.
あのおっさんはな 桂…
お前の首を取るために➡
わざわざ あんな人形をこさえて
お前を おびき出したんだよ｡
You guys were duped.
(全蔵)お前ら
だまされてたんだよ ﾍﾍｯ｡
ﾂﾞﾗく～ん｡ おい ﾂﾞﾗ君｡
Zura-kun... Hey, Zura-kun...
どういうこと？
What's going on?
(桂)そういえば…➡
Come to think of it...
前日に そばの おあげ 取り合って
ｹﾝｶしたの 忘れてた｡
I forgot that we had a fight yesterday over who'd get Oage in their soba.
[Note: Oage = fried tofu on top of hot soba]
お前 それ ただ ｹﾝｶして
出てっただけじゃねえか！
That means she just left the house because of the fight!
ふざけんじゃねえ！
今までの苦労 返せ～!!
Gimme a break!! You owe us for all the trouble!
♪♪～
Hello! I have something to ask you.
(桂)たのもう！
お伺いしたいことがあるのだが…｡
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ 捜したぞ！
お前 今まで何を…｡
Elizabeth, I've been looking all over for you. What were you doing?
(女)ちょっと なに？
新聞？ 断って｡
What? The newspaper?
Can't you say "no"? They never let up. I don't have any money for it.
最近 しつこいのよね｡
んな金 ねえっつうの｡
(女)それより
私 今日も遅くなるから➡
Anyway, I'll be late coming home again tonight. For dinner,
夕飯 冷蔵庫のﾊﾝﾊﾞｰｸﾞ
ﾁﾝして食べて｡
just take some hamburger out of the freezer and nuke it.
Eh, frozen food again? I'm getting tired of it. It's not fair.
(小ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)え～ また 冷凍もの？
もう飽きたよ｡
母ちゃんばっかり ずりぃ｡
ﾎﾞｸ 知ってんだからな｡
I already know Mom puts on a lot of makeup and goes out with an unknown man to have tasty food.
母ちゃん いっつも 化粧して
知らない男の人と➡
自分だけ おいしいもん
食べてんの… ｸﾞﾎｯ！
(女)ほら ｱﾝﾀが ﾜｶﾞﾏﾏ言うから➡
Now look! You're being selfish. You made your father angry!
お父さん
怒っちゃったじゃないの｡
Elizabeth, where are you? Elizabeth!
(桂)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ… どこだ？
(桂)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ～！
[Preview]
Hey, Sadaharu! How did you get so big?
The next episode... "Walk Your Dog at an Appropriate Speed."
[Suddenly Sadaharu grows enormous and is the center of media attention.]
[And who are Ane and Mone, the self-proclaimed beautiful shrine maiden sisters?]